Email: hello@gmoss.caPhone: (416) 702-5937GitHub: www.github.com/grambamPortfolio: www.gmoss.ca

Graham Moss

About Me

Certified Firefighter and Full-Stack Developer with 4+ years of extensive experience developing software and web applications. Adaptive, enthusiastic, and a passion to learn and write great code. Currently specializing in Javascript technologies.

Technical Skills

Languages & Frameworks - Javascript, Typescript, Node, React, AngularJS, PIXI.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Tools - WordPress, Git, Microsoft Office Suite, Visual Studio Code, VMware Workstation, Adobe Photoshop, AWS, Heroku

Soft Skills - Teamwork, Adaptability, Working Under Pressure, Enthusiasm, Work Ethic

Experience

Stock Options Trader, Toronto, Ontario

June 2020 - Present

- Used the skills I learned as a developer to help analyze market news and trends
- Worked in a fast-paced environment under pressure while collaborating with other traders

Lead Interactions Developer, Vretta Inc, Toronto, Ontario

July 2019 - June 2020

- Worked with visual and instructional designers to determine scope and development time of new components
- Documented sections of our lesson creation engine to allow our lesson designers and other developers to have all the information they need in their day to day
- Lead discussions on & implemented best practices and ways to improve workflow throughout our systems

- Gave feedback on storyboards which often made it to the final product
- Created an onboarding process to help new coworkers hit the ground running on their first day

Software Developer, Vretta Inc, Toronto, Ontario

April 2018 - July 2019

- Helped build, maintain and upgrade a state of the art mathematics lesson creation engine using HTML/CSS/Javascript/AngularJS
- Developed tools and components used to create interactive cloud-based math lessons using Typescript/PIXI.JS
- Ensured cross-browser and cross-platform compatibility of all components
- Pushed new features daily to our lesson creation engine, optimizing efficiency and ease of use for our lesson designers

Freelance Web Developer, Toronto, Ontario

May 2017 - April 2018

- Built a financial application front to back from the ground up, which is now being showcased to banks and wealth management firms
- Helped a lighting professional at the AGO get more exposure by setting him up with a portfolio website
- Overhauled a SickKids / UofT research site, increasing performance and user experience

Education

Bitmaker Labs, Toronto, Ontario

January 2017 - April 2017

- Learned and quickly implemented technical skills to apply them to real world projects
- Collaborated extensively on projects, many of which can be seen on my Github page or portfolio website
- Excelled in team organization and leadership